咖啡店在67街和莱克斯街交汇处南面
Coffee shop's on the south side of 67th and Lex.
从65街横向穿过公园
Take the 65th street transverse across the park.
第五大道游客太多  交通太堵
Freaking tourists on 5th avenue always screw up traffic.
-是麦迪森  -估计她要迟到
- It's Madison. - Probably running late.
-小贱人  -麦迪森
- Hey, bitch. - Hey, Madison.
你们一定很"惊讶"  不过我要迟到了
Sure this comes as a shock to you, but I'm running late.
当然
Of course you are.
我马上就过去...
I'll meet you there as soon as --
只是我的傻帽长曲棍球奖杯
Just my stupid lacrosse trophy.
我五分钟后就出门
Anyways, I'm on my way in five.
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
听到什么
Uh, hear what?
等下  别挂电话
Hold on. Stay with me.
是谁
Who's there?
有人吗
Hello?
天呐
Oh, my God.
麦迪森
Madison?!
要不要放点音乐
Uh, shall I put on a little music?
你想让我性致盎然吗  卡塞尔
Are you trying to get me in the mood, Castle?
是的  兴致盎然来挑选
Yes, I am -- in the mood to select
一支出色的婚礼乐队
one of these amazing wedding bands.
我已经筛选掉很多了  就剩最后五支
I've weeded out the hacks and selected five finalists.
乐队
A band?
没有DJ算什么派对啊
What's a party without a deejay?
这话随口一说  是吧
That's rhetorical, right?
拜托  卡塞尔  我可不想
Come on, Castle, I don't want
某个俗气的乐队队长在咱俩跳第一支舞
some cheesy band leader trying to imitate Sinatra
《巫术》的时候在边上模仿西纳特拉
when we're dancing our first dance to "Witchcraft".
我要老蓝眼睛本人[西纳特拉昵称]
I want Ol' Blue Eyes himself.
可惜  他没空[98年过世]
Uh, well, sadly, he's not available.
但DJ可以播放他的唱片
No, but his recordings are via a deejay.
能先倒回去吗  我们为什么要跳《巫术》
Can we go back a second? Why would we be dancing to "Witchcraft"?
因为这是我们的歌
'cause it's our song.
什么时候的事
Since when?
自从我们去年夏天在汉普顿斯的卡拉OK酒吧唱过
Since we sang it at the karaoke bar in the Hamptons last summer.
我们的歌不是
I thought our song was
布鲁斯·斯普林斯汀的《黑夜起舞》吗
Bruce Springsteen's "Dancing In the Dark".
什么时候的事
Since when?
自从我让灯塔酒吧的老板
Since I had the boss pull you onstage
拉你上台模仿柯特妮·考克斯[老友记女演员]
Courtney-Cox style at the Beacon.
我们没有属于自己的歌吗
Do we not have a song?
我们肯定有的吧
We must have a song.
我们的歌就是这铃声
It looks like they're playing it now.
萨顿区发生凶杀案
Murder at Sutton Place.
好高档的凶杀地点
Fancy address for a homicide.
有钱人家
Fancy family.
死者麦迪森·博蒙特是高三...
Our victim, Madison Beaumont -- she was a senior at, uh --
菲克罗夫特预备学校  我认得这个饰章
Faircroft Preparatory Academy. I recognize the crest.
我成功道路上去过的众多学校中的一所
One of the many schools I attended on my road to greatness.
有打斗迹象
Okay, so, there's signs of struggle.
看来麦迪森反抗了
Looks like Madison put up a fight.
她一个人在家吗
Was she here alone?
是的  父母晚上出去了
Yeah. Parents were gone for the evening.
母亲是设计师
Mother's a designer.
父亲是很厉害的辩护律师
Father's some high-powered defense attorney.
强行入室吗
Forced entry?
不是  家里也没丢东西
Nope. Nothing's missing, either,
可能不是盗窃出了岔子
so probably wasn't a burglary gone wrong.
椽上的是血吗
Is that blood up there on the rafter?
是的  她的血
Yes, and it's hers.
怎么到这上面去的
How'd it get up there?
就我们所知
Well, as far as we can tell,
是凶手把麦迪森扔上去的
our killer threw Madison up there.
可能这就是她的死因
Which is probably what killed her.
她有严重颅脑损伤
She has a major intracranial injury.
她被扔上了天花板
She was thrown against the ceiling?
这简直是超人的行为  几乎不可能实现
That is a superhuman feat bordering on physically impossible.
好了  卡塞尔  说出来吧
Okay, Castle, let's hear it.
你有什么稀奇古怪的理论
What's your outlandish theory?
这还不明显吗
Isn't it obvious?
麦迪森惹恼了绿巨人
Madison made the Hulk angry.
不管是不是绿巨人
Well, Hulk or no Hulk,
肝温表明死亡时间
liver temp puts the time of death
在今晚八点到十点
somewhere between 8:00 and 10:00 tonight.
符合报警电话的时间
Which fits with our 911 call.
电话是在9点08分由一位的哥打进来的
Call came in at 9:08 from a cabbie
报警人声称这个地址有人收到攻击
saying that someone was being attacked at this address.
出租车  他目睹整个凶案了吗
A cabbie? Did he witness the murder?
还不清楚
We're still not clear on that.
我们还在找他
We're trying to track him down.
同时  埃斯波在警局跟麦迪森的家人谈话
Meanwhile, Espo's talking with Madison's family back at the precinct.
要是我们待在家没出去就好了
If only we'd stayed home instead of going to dinner.
我们想给麦迪森一点空间
We wanted to give Madison her space.
我们最近经常吵架
We've been fighting a lot.
吵些什么
About what?
她不学习  不跟我们说话...
Her not studying, her not talking to us --
就是平常的青少年琐事
normal teenage stuff.
我得问问
I have to ask.
你们知道有谁想伤害你们的女儿吗
Do you know of anybody who might want to hurt your daughter?
没有
No. No, of course not.
麦迪森朋友非常多
Madison had so many friends.
她最爱做的事就是
Her favorite thing to do
策划活动请大家一起玩
was plan events for everyone to enjoy.
冬季舞会就在两...
The winter ball is in two --
两天后
two days.
我们认为凶手
Well, we think whoever did this
一定非常强壮  肌肉发达
had to be unusually strong -- muscular, maybe.
你们知道她认识的人当中有谁...
Do you know of anybody in her life --
天呐
Oh, my God.
查尔斯  会不会是莱利
Charles, what about Riley?
莱利是谁
Uh, who's Riley?
莱利·米奇姆  她的前男友
Riley Mitchum -- her ex-boyfriend.
麦迪森上个月跟他分手了
Madison broke up with him last month.
他不是很能接受
He didn't take it well.
莱利·米奇姆
Riley Mitchum --
根据菲克罗夫特橄榄球队官网的资料
According to the Faircroft football website,
他身高1米88  体重95公斤
He's 6'2" And 210 pounds.
他就是你说的绿巨人  卡塞尔
There's your Hulk, Castle.
杀人可跟菲克罗夫特
Well, though murder is at odds
灌输给学生的价值观格格不入
with the values instilled in a Faircroft man.
高中以后我就没来过这里了
I haven't been back here since I was a senior.
你就是从这儿毕业的咯
So, this is where you graduated, huh?
本来是那样的  如果不是
Well, I would have, if it wasn't for the fact
某夜我和小伙伴们溜进学校
that one night, my buddies and I sneaked in
把一头奶牛推上12层楼的楼顶的话
and pushed a cow up 12 flights of stairs onto the roof.
-奶牛  真的吗  -嗯
- A cow? Really? - Yep.
然后呢
So, what happened?
你们被开除了吗
Did you guys get expelled?
不  只有我  不像其他人那样团结一心
No, just me. I wasn't connected like my buddies were.
我成绩好不合群  所以被开除了
I was the scholarship kid, so I got the boot.
你后来发展得很好啊
Well, I think you turned out all right.
英雄所见略同
Me, too.
这事太可怕了
Man, this is awful.
麦迪森是我的初恋啊
I mean, Madison was, like, my first love.
她把你甩了  你一定很受伤吧
Must've hurt when she broke up with you.
等等  你们理解错了
Wait, y-you guys got it all wrong.
是我甩了她
I broke up with her.
她母亲不是这么说的
Mm, not according to her mom.
她父母什么都不知道  好吗
Man, her -- her parents didn't have a clue, okay?
几个月前
A couple months ago,
麦迪森开始每晚都外出
Madison started going out all times of the night.
也不肯告诉我她在忙些什么
She wouldn't tell me what she was up to.
她是去见其他人吗
Was she seeing someone else?
我觉得是这样  但我没查出是谁
I figured she had to be, but I never found out who.
你昨晚在哪
Where were you last night?
跟我的新女友在一起  你们可以去问她
Was with...My new girl. You can ask her.
名字告诉我  我要确认一下
Okay, well, I'm gonna need a name to confirm that.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-贝克特  -莱恩
- Hey, Beckett. - Hey, Ryan.
你去查一下
I need you to check into
麦迪森的通话记录和最近的活动
Madison's phone records and recent activity.
找找她最新结识了什么人
Look for anyone new in her life.
好的  我们找到那个的哥了
You got it. Meantime, we located that cabbie.
他说两名女乘客在视频通话里看到袭击了
He says two female passengers saw the attack on a video call.
她们让他报警
They told him to call 911.
然后就逃下车了
Then they bolted from the cab.
但他把姑娘们上车的地点告诉我们了
But he gave us the building where he picked the girls up,
门卫认出了她们
and the doorman there I.D.'d them.
-她们现在在哪  -就在你那
- Where are they now? - Same place you are.
克丽丝·霍华德  希拉里·库珀
Kris Howard? Hillary Cooper?
是关于麦迪森的  对吧
It's about Madison, isn't it?
凶案当时我们正在视频通话
We were facetiming with her when it happened.
太恐怖了
It was horrifying.
那你们为什么不报警
Well, then, why didn't you call 911?
我们太害怕
We just panicked.
我们吓坏了
We were scared.
怕什么
Of what?
害怕成为下一个
That we'd be next.
下一个  什么  凶手看见你们了
Next? What, did the attacker see you?
没有  但是
No, but...
什么
What?
两周前
Look, uh, two weeks ago,
在食堂发生了一件事
this thing happened in the cafeteria --
校长说过我们不能谈论这件事
The principal said we're not supposed to talk about it.
什么事
About what?
你们还是去问他吧
You'll have to ask him.
校长稍后就到
The principal will be with you in just a moment.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡塞尔  这都说不通啊
Castle, none of this adds up.
那两个女生在怕什么
What were those girls so afraid of?
食堂到底发生了什么事
What happened in that cafeteria?
我本该给出一个推论
I'd offer a theory,
但我在忙着回忆课后留校的时光
but I'm too busy having detention flashbacks.
你一定在这条过道上待过很长时间
You must've spent a lot of time in this hallway.
比在教室的时间还长
More than I did in class.
我赌那校长恨你
I bet that principal hated you.
"恨"这个字的程度好像还不够强烈
I'm wondering if "Hate" is a strong-enough word.
邓南校长雇了辆吊车才把奶牛从楼顶弄走
Principal Dunnan had to hire a crane to get that cow off the roof.
但我敢肯定那老牛已经退休了
But I'm sure that old battle-ax has long since retired.
放牧去了  打个比喻
Put out to pasture, so to speak.
是牛的比喻吗  罗杰斯先生
Is that a bovine reference, Mr. Rodgers?
邓南校长  您还在这
Principal Dunnan, you're, uh...still here.
遗憾的是  你回来了
And, sadly, you have returned.
我看到你成功地把自己从
I see you have managed to extricate yourself
不良少年的人生中解救出来了  罗杰斯先生
from a life of delinquency, Mr. Rodgers,
还变成了作家  不怎样的
and become a writer... of sorts.
事实上  现在是卡塞尔先生了
Well, actually, it's, uh, Mr. Castle now.
在我眼里你永远是罗杰斯
You'll always be Rodgers to me.
我们想问问你关于麦迪森·博蒙特的事
Uh, we need to ask you a few questions about Madison Beaumont.
真是件不幸的事
It's a terrible business.
对整个菲克罗夫特大家庭来说真是个悲剧
It's a real tragedy for the entire Faircroft family.
她的两个朋友  克丽丝·霍华德和希拉里·库珀
Two of her friends, Kris Howard and Hillary Cooper,
从视频通话中目击了凶案
witnessed the murder over facetime,
但她们不愿意说  我们想知道原因
but they're not willing to talk. We need to know why.
显然  这跟最近
Apparently, it's related to something
发生在食堂的事有关
that happened in the cafeteria recently?
邓南先生
Mr. Dunnan?
我可以说
I'll tell you,
但你们得答应不将其公之于众
but you have to agree not to make any of this public.
这会有损学校的声誉
It will damage the school's reputation.
我们是在调查谋杀案
We are in the middle of a murder investigation.
你没有谈条件的资格
You're not exactly in the position to bargain here.
好吧
Very well.
他竟然会用电脑
I'm surprised he can use a computer.
我是老了不是聋了  罗杰斯先生
I am old, not deaf, Mr. Rodgers,
而且高科技也难不倒我
and undaunted by technology.
两周前
Two weeks ago,
一个学生用手机拍下了整个事件
a student captured this event on his cellphone.
-事件  -没错
- "Event"? - Yes.
我删除了他手机上的视频
I removed the video from his phone.
因为在事情真相大白前
I didn't want anyone to see it
我还不想让其他人知道
until the incident was fully understood.
艾丽·比林斯
Alli Billings?
-辣  -确实
- Hot. - So hot.
-好吧  李琪·吉尔森呢  -少来了
- All right, all right. Rikki Gelson? - No way!
我觉得还行
I'd still hit it!
所谓的事件就是高中
High-school guys playing "Hot-or-not" --
-小男生给女生排名吗  -接着看
- that's the event? - Just wait.
乔丹·吉布斯觉得怎么样
Okay, Jordan Gibbs -- hot or not?
怎么搞的
What?
乔丹是个好学生
Jordan is a good student,
但是总受欺负
but she's a bit of a black sheep.
午饭吃什么  乔丹  油毡吗
What's for lunch, Jordan -- linoleum?
她总是被被害人及其朋友欺负
And she's being bullied by our victim and her friends.
接着看
Keep watching.
这  才是所谓的事件
That... is the event.
被排外
The outcast...
被坏女孩们欺负
the mean girls,
爆发的愤怒无意中触发了意念移物能力
the rage that erupts in a telekinetic attack.
简直是真实版的《魔女嘉莉》
This is a real-life "Carrie."
绝对是人为的恶作剧
This has got to be a hoax.
混乱一开始我就冲进了食堂
I ran into the cafeteria as soon as the commotion started.
现场乱作一团  即便是恶作剧
The place was in shambles, but if it was a hoax,
作恶者也没有留下证据
the perpetrator left no evidence.
我们需要备份一下视频用以研究
Okay, well, we'll need a copy of this for analysis.
-之前有类似的事发生过吗  -没有
- Now, has anything like this happened before? - No.
其实有的
Um, yes --
就在案发现场
at the crime scene.
这完美的解释了麦迪森头上的撞伤
This explains Madison's head wound,
还有横梁上的血迹
the blood on the rafters.
就是说乔丹用念力将她丢上了房梁
Jordan threw her up there using the powers of her mind --
也就是意念移物
telekinesis.
乔丹和麦迪森之前有过节吗
Is there a history of trouble between Jordan and Madison?
都是最近的事
Not until recently.
我听说
I heard a rumor
麦迪森和朋友们总是骚扰乔丹
that Madison and her friends were harassing Jordan.
于是找乔丹谈了谈
I reached out to her,
但她说想自己解决
but she said she would prefer handling things herself.
如果这就是她的解决办法
Well, if this is how she handles things,
克丽丝和希拉里会害怕也就在情理之中了
no wonder Kris and Hillary are scared.
我们得找乔丹谈谈
We need to speak with Jordan.
我去叫她
I'll have her pulled from class.
真想快点告诉史蒂芬这个案子
Cannot wait to tell Stephen about this case.
-谁  -史蒂芬·金[《魔女嘉莉》作者]  太难以置信了
- Hmm? Stephen king. He won't believe it --
真实版的《魔女嘉莉》
a real-life Carrie.
卡塞尔  我还不能肯定
Castle, uh, I can't say
食堂和麦迪森卧室究竟发生了什么
what happened in the cafeteria or in Madison's bedroom yet.
但有一点我能肯定
But I can say this --
这两个女孩之间的纠纷确实让
the animosity between those two girls
乔丹成为了案件重要的利害关系人
is what makes Jordan a person of interest
但绝非异能故事里的主人公
and not your telekinetic fantasy.
很抱歉  可是乔丹不见了
I'm very sorry, but I'm afraid that Jordan is gone.
什么叫不见了
What do you mean she's gone?
有学生说
It seems a student in her class came in and told everyone
警察来调查麦迪森的事
the N.Y.P.D. was here asking about Madison.
乔丹心烦意乱地离开了学校
Jordan got very upset and left the campus.
她的老师刚打来电话告诉我的
Her teacher just called to inform us.
乔丹还是不接电话
Jordan's still not answering.
只能接通留言箱
It just keeps going right to voicemail.
你确定她不在我那吗
You sure she's not at my house?
我的搭档去查看过了  她不在您家
I sent my partner in to check. She wasn't there.
帕朋夫人  乔丹有没有跟你提过
Ms. Papen, did Jordan ever mention
一个叫麦迪森·博蒙特的人
a Madison Beaumont to you?
我记忆中没有
No, not that I can remember.
-她昨天在家吗  -不在
- Was she home last night? - No.
她11点多才回来
She was out till after 11:00.
-去哪里了  -不知道
- Out where? - I don't know.
我哥哥和嫂子在车祸中去世了
Look, my brother and his wife died in a car wreck,
所以我收养了乔丹
and I took Jordan in.
我责无旁贷
That's what you do.
但我要兼两份工才能养活我俩
But I have two jobs just to keep us afloat,
我昨天8点多才到家  她不在
and I wasn't home till 8:00, and she was gone.
那她回来时看起来有什么异常吗
How did she seem when she got home?
很安静  和平时一样
Quiet, as usual.
我们不怎么说话
We didn't talk much,
她直接回她的屋里去了
and then she just went straight to her room.
哈维
Hey, Javi...
过来一下行吗
Got a second?
当然  失陪一下
Yeah. Excuse me.
警探
Detective...
我知道情况对乔丹十分不利
I-I know what this looks like, but..
但是乔丹真的是个好孩子
Jordan is a really good kid.
她靠着自己挣来的奖学金
You know, she got a scholarship herself
才进的这所高中
to that fancy school, and, I mean,
她不会轻易放弃这一切的
She just -- she wouldn't throw that away, you know?
她绝不会干这种事
She -- she just wouldn't do this.
绝对是乔丹干的
Yeah. It was totally Jordan.
毋庸置疑
No doubt.
你们并没有看到她
But you never actually saw her.
可是我们没看到任何人
Well, we didn't see anyone.
就好像是什么隐形的力量
It was as if some invisible force
像丢洋娃娃似的把麦迪森丢来丢去
threw madison around the room like a rag doll.
和乔丹在食堂
The same way Jordan attacked
-攻击我们时一模一样  -没错
- us in the cafeteria. - Yeah.
那是因为你们故意撞翻了她的盘子
After you knocked into her as she carried a tray full of food.
我们知道欺负她不对  但...
Look, we know it was wrong of us to mess with her, but...
她很古怪  你懂吗
I mean, she's odd, you know?
她对怪异的东西感兴趣
She's into weird stuff.
-漫画书么  -乔丹房间里都是这些
- Comic books? - Yeah, I found them all over Jordan's room.
小题大做  她或许就爱看X战警
Big deal -- she's an X-men fan.
或许因为她也是变种人
Maybe 'cause she's one of them.
看看这些
Check it out.
《意念移物大释放》
"Telekinesis unleashed."
《开发意念移物能力》
"Developing telekinetic powers."
《初学隔空取物》
"Telekinesis for beginners."
还有这个
And then...there's this.
得了吧  老兄  严肃点行吗
Come on, bro. Let's be serious. Yeah?
你看这够严肃了吧
Is this serious enough for you?
这是死者的照片
That's our victim.
它就贴在乔丹书桌上方
I found it taped over Jordan's desk.
她总是看这些书吗
Was she always into this stuff?
不  是几个礼拜前才开始的
Uh, no. It started a few weeks ago.
她问我提前要生活费
She asked for an advance on her allowance
去买了这些书
and then went and bought all these books.
怎么了
Why?
乔丹的朋友呢
What about Jordan's friends?
他们会知道她在哪儿吗
Would they know where she is?
她的朋友不多
She doesn't have a lot of friends.
多数时候她都对着电脑
She spends most of her time in front of her computer.
你介意看我们看一下她的电脑吗
Do you mind if we take a look at it?
这有助于找出她的去向
It might help us find out where she went.
不介意
No, that's fine.
在她这样十几岁的年纪
Well, she's a teenage girl.
肯定会有一起玩的小伙伴
There's got to be somebody that she's hanging with.
是有个男孩偶尔会来
Well, there's one boy that comes around now and then.
乔丹生病的时候给她拿来了作业
He brought Jordan's homework to the house when she was sick.
名字叫卢卡斯
His name is Lucas.
卢卡斯·特洛伊  他就在那儿
Lucas Troy. And there he is.
"星空骑士"  冬季舞会
Ah, "A Starry Knight" -- The Winter Ball.
我告诉过你邓南校长是在毕业舞会前开除我的吗
Did I tell you principal Dunnan expelled me just before prom?
卡塞尔  你居然没能参加自己的毕业舞会
Castle, no! You didn't get to go to your own prom?
我的舞伴原本是奥德拉·道伯森
And my date would've been Audra Dobson --
超级火辣
So unbelievably hot.
如果能给你点安慰的话  我也错过了舞会
Well, if it's any consolation, I missed my prom as well.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
卢卡斯·特洛伊吗
Lucas Troy?
你好  我是凯特·贝克特警探
Hi. I'm detective Kate Beckett.
他是我同事  理查德·卡塞尔
This is my colleague, Richard Castle.
-有时间谈谈吗  -有啊  不好意思
- Do you have a minute? - Yeah. Ye-- s-sorry.
我只是想在明天舞会前把这个弄完
I'm just trying to get this done for tomorrow's dance.
整个礼拜我都在忙这事儿
I've been at it all week.
现在我的肺里面
At this point, the inside of my lungs
可能都是天蓝色的了
are probably cerulean blue.
真奇怪他们怎么没有延迟舞会
I'm surprised they're not postponing the dance.
麦迪森的父母坚持如期举行舞会来纪念她
Madison's parents are insisting it go on in her memory.
真是神奇  即使她已经死了
It's amazing -- even after she's dead,
所有话题还是围着她转
everything's still all about her.
很明显你不喜欢她
Obviously, you're not a fan.
我不喜欢她对待别人的方式
I didn't like how she treated people.
是指乔丹·吉布斯吗
People like Jordan Gibbs?
对  但乔丹不可能报复的
Yeah, but there's no way Jordan would retaliate.
她不会对任何人动手
The girl wouldn't raise her hand to anyone.
她没必要动"手"
She didn't have to,
要是她能隔空移物的话
not when she has flying chairs in her arsenal.
我听到传言了
I heard the rumors.
虽然我当时不在食堂
I wasn't there in the cafeteria,
但我肯定那不是她干的
but I'm sure she had nothing to do with that.
你今天早上第一节课是和她一起上的
No, but you were in her first-period class this morning.
你知道她去哪儿了吗
Do you know where she went?
她什么也没对我说  就这么走了
She didn't say a word to me. She just -- she just took off.
卢卡斯  我们跟你老师谈过
Lucas, we spoke with your teacher.
她说乔丹走后你马上也走了
She said that you left right after Jordan did.
你离开了15分钟  是去哪儿了
You were gone for 15 minutes. Where'd you go?
我看得出来她很不安
I-I could see she was really upset,
我只是想看看她好不好
so I just wanted to see if she was okay.
所以我就跟着她...
So I went after her...
但在4/5/6号线86街地铁站  我跟丢了
but I lost her, uh, at the 4/5/6 subway station on 86th.
我们先来看看食堂录像
Okay, so, let's start with the cafeteria video.
看不出乔丹·吉布斯或其他人
There's no indication that Jordan Gibbs or anyone else
移动桌椅的迹象
is moving the tables and chairs.
坦白说  我也解释不了
Frankly, I can't explain what we're seeing here.
我想我能给你们解释解释
Well, I think I can offer an explanation.
那通她打给朋友的视频电话呢
Uh, what about the FaceTime call made to Madison's friends?
有办法拿到视频吗
Is there any way to retrieve that?
视频电话就像电话一样
A video call is like a phone call.
如果没有人录下来
Unless someone's recording it,
电话挂断  数据也就没了
once the call ends, the data is gone.
至于乔丹的电脑嘛  搜索历史显示
As for Jordan's laptop, browser history suggests
最近两个礼拜  她花了很长时间
she spent hours obsessing on all things telekinesis,
研究意念移物
starting two weeks ago.
正好是在
Right about the time
她用意念砸了食堂之后
she telekinetically rearranged the cafeteria.
很显然  乔丹意识到自己有某些超能力
Clearly, Jordan realized she had powers
想要理解它们
and was trying to understand them.
这和《魔女嘉莉》惊人地相似啊
This is exactly like the movie "Carrie."
对  和电影惊人地相似  因为都是虚构的
Yes, exactly like the movie -- fictional.
乔丹没有什么超能力
Jordan doesn't have powers.
拿到了乔丹的通话记录
Got Jordan's phone records.
通信服务供应商说她的手机关机了
Her service provider says that her phone's been turned off,
但她离开学校的时候打了个电话
but she made one call right when she ditched school.
-打给谁  -号码属于一家叫亨德森诊断所的地方
- To who? - Number's listed to a Henderson Diagnostics,
但我找不到他们到底是做什么的
And I can't find any info on what they do, exactly.
打电话过去也没人接
But when I called, there was no answer,
也没有语音留言和短信
no voicemail or message, either.
-你有拿到地址吗  -是的  布鲁克林  4/5号线那站
- Did you get an address? - Uh, yeah -- Brooklyn, off the 4/5 line.
乔丹来这个地方干什么
What was Jordan doing all the way out here?
这里离她的家还有学校都很远
I mean, it's miles away from her house, the school, uh --
没人知道乔丹有任何朋友
Just because nobody knows who Jordan's friends are.
并不代表她真的没有任何朋友
Doesn't mean she doesn't have any.
她朋友都会来这种地方玩吗
And her friends hang out in a place like this?
你好
Hi.
纽约警察  我要问你几个问题
NYPD. I'd like to ask you a few que--
你一定是为博士而来
Y-you must be here for the doctor.
他正在上课
He's in session now.
跟着我走
Follow me.
打扰一下  纽约警察
Excuse me. NYPD.
我们来寻
We're looking...
找
for...
我想我们找对地方了
I think we're in the right place.
-你是怎么做到的  -精神专注的力量
- How did you do that? - The power of a focused mind.
是嘛  我在拉斯维加斯看到过这种把戏
Yeah, I saw that trick in Vegas.
你是谁  这是个什么地方
So, who are you? What is this place?
我是拉姆帕纳尔博士
I am Dr. Rampanel.
这个地方是我的实验室
And this place is my lab,
而且我所做的并不是魔术
and what I do is not magic.
那么到底是什么呢
So, then, what is it?
我在麻省理工学院教生物物理学
I teach biophysics at M.I.T.
我从亨德森那租下这个地方
I rent this space from Henderson
来开展我在意念移物方面的研究
to conduct my research in telekinesis.
你研究意念移物吗
You study telekinesis?
我教人们如何激发出他们的潜能
I teach people how to unlock their potential.
我猜是收费的
For a fee, I'm guessing.
如果他们付得够多
If they pay you enough,
你会让他们相信自己是特别的
you make them believe they're special.
我看出来你是个怀疑者
I see you're a skeptic.
大多数没有天赋的人都是如此
Most ungifted are.
你怎么看乔丹·吉布斯
What can you tell us about Jordan Gibbs?
对了  乔丹
Ah, yes. Jordan.
我记得她上周过来给自己做评估
She came by last week, I think, to have herself evaluated.
她做得怎么样  让我猜猜看
How did she do? Uh, let me guess --
太出色了
Off the charts.
我真的不能讨论我的研究结果
I really can't discuss my findings.
上周吗
Last week?
但是她今早往这里打过电话
But she called here this morning.
事实上  她确实打过电话
In fact, she did, yes.
她说了些什么
And... what did she say?
她很害怕
Uh, she was frightened.
乔丹还不知道如何控制自己的能力
You see, Jordan doesn't yet know how to control her powers.
她有来见你吗
So, did she come here to see you?
是的  但她现在已经走了
Yes. But she's gone now.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
如果你不说实话的话
And if you don't tell me the truth,
我会以妨碍司法公正罪
I will arrest you for obstruction.
-和窝藏嫌犯罪逮捕你  -别说了
- and harboring a fugitive  - Stop.
别逼他了
Leave him alone.
他只是想保护我
He's just trying to protect me.
她甚至长得就有点像魔女嘉莉
She even kind of looks like Carrie.
才不是
No, she does not!
再说了  这么个瘦小女生怎么能
Besides, how would that little, skinny girl
把麦迪森扔到天花板上
throw Madison up against the ceiling?
借助于我们还无法理解的能力
With powers we have yet to comprehend.
在里面小心点  别惹她生气
Be careful in there. Don't anger her.
我们不知道她有多大的能力
We don't know what she's capable of.
你说得对
You're right.
你或许应该跟我一块进去
You should probably go in there with me...
保护我
For protection.
找你找得好辛苦啊  乔丹
You're a hard girl to find, Jordan.
我必须要离菲克罗夫特远点
I had to get away from Faircroft.
每个人都在私下谈论说
Everyone was whispering about
我是杀害麦迪森的罪魁祸首
how I was the one who killed Madison.
他们为什么要这么说
And why would they say that?
是因为麦迪森是你的死敌吗
Is it because Madison was your nemesis?
她以前并不是
She didn't used to be.
很长一段时间
For the longest time,
我都被麦迪森和她的小团体所无视
I was invisible to Madison and her bitch clique...
就像我被大部分人所无视一样
Just like I am to most people.
然后  上个月
And then, last month,
放完寒假回来的第一个早上
first morning back after winter break,
我在图书馆里读书
I was in the library reading,
然后我偶然在俄国文学区碰到她
and I ran into her in the Russian lit section.
她接着就大发雷霆
And she got all pissed,
说我不能告诉任何人我在那里见过她
Saying I couldn't tell anyone that I'd seen her there.
-她为什么生气  -我完全不知道
- What was she angry about? - I have no idea.
也许她不想让任何人知道
Maybe she didn't want anyone to know
她还是会学习的
that she actually studies.
但是  那天晚些时候  麦迪森就开始针对我
But then, later that day, Madison started messing with me,
从此就一发不可收拾了
and it just got worse from there.
所以你在食堂演了那出闹剧
So you pulled that stunt in the cafeteria
想让她对你有所畏惧
to make her scared of you.
我只是想制止他们的行为
I just wanted them to stop!
这就是你杀麦迪森的原因吗
Is that why you killed Madison?
我猜是吧  我不知道
I guess so! I-I don't know!
这是我紧张时的习惯动作
It's a nervous habit.
乔丹  不能猜来猜去
Jordan, there's no guessing here.
你要么是杀了麦迪森要么没杀
Either you did or you didn't kill Madison.
我很生气
I got so angry...
然后东西就开始在食堂到处乱飞
and stuff just started flying around the cafeteria.
然后我希望麦迪森去死
And then I wished for Madison to be dead,
我再听到她的消息时  她真的就死了
And the next thing I knew, she was!
这一定是我做的  对吧
It had to be me, right?
你昨晚八点到十点在哪里
Where were you between 8:00 and 10:00 P.M. last night?
我在阿斯托利亚的露露咖啡厅学习
I was studying at Lulu's Cafe in Astoria.
我们得放她走
We're gonna have to kick her loose.
服务生确定乔丹在11点之前一直在
Waitress confirmed that Jordan was at the cafe
皇后区的咖啡厅里
in Queens till 11:00.
那她是不可能杀害麦迪森的
So she couldn't have killed madison.
不是仅凭她的双手
Not with her bare hands,
可谁知道她的隔空取物能力能伸展多远
but who knows how far her secret telekinetic powers might reach?
事实上
Well, it turns out our victim
被害人也有着她自己的小秘密
might've had some secrets of her own.
你找到了她是在和谁约会吗
Did you track down whoever Madison was seeing?
据我所知  她没有在和任何人约会
As far as I can tell, she wasn't seeing anybody.
不过  这里是她的财务报告
But these are her financials.
什么样的高中生会有财务报告
What kind of high-school kid has financials?
麦迪森有
Madison does.
她有一堆信用卡
She had a dozen credit cards,
她把它们都刷爆了
and she was wearing them out
爱马仕手袋  周仰杰鞋子
Hermes handbags, Jimmy Choos.
这可是几万美金的东西
I'm talking tens of thousands of dollars.
那又怎样  他父母很有钱
So what? Her parents were loaded.
是啊  不过她父母可没帮她支付那些
Yeah, but mommy and daddy weren't springing for any of this stuff.
这些卡都是在麦迪森的名下
The cards were in Madison's name,
每月都用她的秘密银行账户付清欠款
paid off every month through her own secret bank account.
那她这些钱都是哪里来的
So where was this money coming from?
这也是我们正在调查的
That's what we're trying to figure out.
另外  还有一长串信用卡记录
Plus, there's more -- a slew of credit-card charges
半夜叫的出租车和便利店消费
for late-night cab rides and convenience-store purchases.
这个倒是和麦迪森前男友的描述吻合
Well, and that fits with what Madison's ex-boyfriend said
说她经常半夜出去夜不归宿
about her staying out to all hours.
也许她只是出去玩  泡泡夜店什么的
Okay, maybe she was going out, hitting the clubs.
是啊  不过  这些都是工作日夜晚
Yeah, but on weeknights?
而且这里没有酒吧或者夜店的记录
And there are no bar or club charges here.
看看这个
And look at this.
记得乔丹和麦迪森的矛盾是怎么来的吗
Remember how Jordan said her troubles with Madison began
刚开学那会儿她俩在图书馆撞见
when school started back up with that run-in at the library?
根据这项出租车记录
According to this taxi charge,
麦迪森那天早上5点就在外面了
Madison was out and about that same morning at 5:00 a.m.
那说明她活动结束之后直接去了学校
Okay, so, she was going straight to school from wherever she was.
可是她为什么要整晚都在外面
But why would she stay out all night
然后去学校的图书馆
and then go to the school library?
她在做什么她不想让乔丹知道的事情
What was she doing she didn't want Jordan to know about?
学生们通过刷卡来进出图书馆
Students use their I.D.s to swipe in and out of the library.
这是麦迪森·博蒙特整个学年
These are all the times Madison Beaumont
进出图书馆的记录
entered and exited during this entire school year.
谢谢
Thank you.
每次麦迪森大清早去图书馆
Okay, so, each one of Madison's early-morning visits
都是在她在外面通宵之后
to the library happened after one of her all-nighters.
她进来之后五分钟就出去了
She swiped in and out within 5 minutes.
我猜她在俄国文学区这里晃可不是要学习
I'm guessing she wasn't hanging out in russian lit to study.
卡塞尔  俄国文学  就在这儿
Castle, russian literature -- it's right here.
多谢Kindle
Thank god for the kindle,
不然我没过几年就要失业了
or I'd be out of a job in a couple of years.
现在的孩子根本不看实体书了
Kids just don't read actual books anymore.
除非是《Voyna I mir》
Unless it's "Voyna I mir" --
《战争与和平》  俄文原版  瞧
"War and peace," In its original russian. And look
这片没有灰尘
-- there's no dust here.
看来最近有人把这本书拿出来过
It's like someone pulled this out recently.
这本书比我印象中的要轻
And it's lighter than I remember Tolstoy being.
这些是银行券吗
Are these bank notes?
这些是债券
These are bonds.
是无记名债券  德国政府发行的
These are bearer bonds, issued by the German government.
这些都是见票即可支付给持票人
These are payable to the bearer,
不会有任何验证
no questions asked.
德国无记名债券
German bearer bonds?
我以为这些只在《虎胆龙威》里有
I thought that only existed in "Die Hard."
麦迪森是怎么搞到这种东西的
How did Madison get her hands on these?
不知道  可这里价值超过一百万美元
I don't know, but there's over a million dollars' worth here.
肯定是哪里搞错了
No, there must be some mistake.
也许她是申请了几张信用卡
She may have applied for some credit cards,
不过麦迪森不可能有如此多现金在银行里
but there's no way Madison had a bank account with this much cash in it.
没有搞错  博蒙特先生
There's no mistake, Mr. Beaumont.
这些钱也只是冰山的一角
And this money is just the tip of the iceberg.
除了疯狂大血拼之外
Well, aside from the shopping sprees,
我们也发现您女儿的信用卡上
We found some odd charges on your daughter's credit cards
在过去几个月有异常消费记录
over the past few months.
出租车记录  都是在深更半夜
For cab rides taken during the middle of the night.
你知道她是去干嘛了吗
Do you have any idea what she was doing
或者她是去哪里了
or where she was going?
这些都是在工作日夜晚
These charges are for weeknights.
上学日夜晚
School nights.
那你们不知道这些
So you weren't aware of this.
不  麦迪森都是在11点上床睡觉
No, Madison was in bed by 11:00 every night, or...
至少我们觉得是
We thought she was.
你们觉得她是不是卷入什么事情里了
Do you think she got mixed up in something,
所以她才会被杀
And...that's the reason she died?
这个我们还不知道
We don't know.
不过我们在学校图书馆里找到了一些东西
But we did find something else in the school library.
在一本被掏空的书里
Inside of a hollowed-out book
书上布满了您女儿的指纹
with your daughter's fingerprints all over it.
你们找到了什么
What did you find?
价230万美元的德国无记名债券
$2.3 million in German bearer bonds.
无记名债券
Bearer bonds?
这些是你的无记名债券吗  博蒙特先生
Are these your bearer bonds, Mr. Beaumont?
不  不是的
Uh, no. No.
那你知道你女儿可能会在哪里得到这些呢
Do you know where your daughter could've gotten them?
查尔斯
Charles?
不知道  非常抱歉
No. Um, I'm sorry.
我们帮不了你
We can't help you.
来  戴安  我们走吧
Come on, Diane. We're done here.
麦迪森的父亲肯定知道这些无记名债券
There's no question Madison's dad knew about those bearer bonds.
如果他们知道有关她女儿之死的信息
Okay, if they have something to do with his daughter's death,
那他为什么不愿意告诉我们呢
then why wouldn't he want to tell us about them?
等我们知道这些债券是哪来的就都清楚了
We're not gonna know until we know where they came from.
我们正在根据债券上的序列号查询信息
We're tracking the serial numbers on the bonds
看看是否能找到最初的持有者
to see if we can locate the original owners,
不过这要花上点时间
but it's gonna take some time.
这女孩究竟卷入什么事情里了
What the hell was this girl mixed up in?
以及这和乔丹的意念移物能力有什么联系
And what does it have to do with Jordan's telekinesis?
没关系  因为乔丹根本就不会意念移物
Nothing, because Jordan is not telekinetic.
那你解释一下食堂的那段录像是怎么回事
Well, explain that cafeteria video.
我解释不了  卡塞尔
I can't, Castle.
但我告诉你  我肯定能找到解释的
But I assure you, I will.
那麦迪森的死又怎么说
And what about Madison's death --
被一股无形力量抛来投去  就像个布娃娃
Being thrown around like a rag doll by an unseen force?
你看不见并不意味着没人搞鬼
Yeah, well, unseen doesn't mean that nobody was there.
而我们应该关注的真正问题是
And the real question that we should be asking
一个17岁的小丫头
is what is a 17-year-old doing
藏着230万不记名债券干什么
with $2.3 million in bearer bonds?
这才是害死她的原因  不是什么超能力杀手
That probably got her killed, not some psychic assassin.
只怕对此我们只能各持己见了
Well, perhaps we'll have to agree to disagree on that,
但是这个我们应该能达成一致
and agree to agree on this.
"《公告牌》评选史上100首最浪漫的歌曲"
"The billboard's top 100 most romantic songs of all time."
我觉得我们的定情歌肯定得在这单子上
I figure our song has got to be on that list somewhere.
别卡塞尔  我才不会从一个什么单子上选歌
No, Castle, I'm not choosing our song off of a list
何况这单子上还有威豹的《给我一些甜蜜》
that includes Def Leppard's "Pour some sugar on me."
我敢肯定这首歌
Uh, that song, I am sure,
在87年点燃了无数艳舞厅恋情
ignited many a strip-club romance in 1987.
1987年啊
1987...
那一年手镯合唱团
A year when the Bangles
教会了我们像埃及人一样走路[该组合名作]
taught us how to walk like an Egyptian,
邦乔维教会了我们如何"活在祈祷中"
Bon Jovi taught us how to live on nothing but a prayer,
瑞克·艾斯里教会了我们怎么笑
and Rick Astley taught us how to laugh.
你感到怀旧是因为你今天又被拉回了
You're feeling nostalgic after getting pulled back in time
在菲克罗夫特预科学校上学的时光
to your days at Faircroft Prep.
是啊  重游故地感觉很奇妙
Yeah, it was strange going back.
一切看起来都小了点  却又和当年并无二致
Everything seems smaller, yet unchanged.
走廊还是那个走廊
I mean, the hallways are the same.
校长还是那位校长
The principal is the same.
连舞会横幅上的标识都没变
Same banners for school dances.
你为什么没参加你的毕业舞会
A-and why didn't you go to your prom?
我敢肯定17岁妙龄的凯瑟琳·贝克特
I'm sure a 17-year-old Katherine Beckett
有不少追求者
had many a young suitor.
只不过当年的叛逆小凯特太酷了
Yeah, except rebel Becks was a little too cool
看不上傻乎乎的舞会  所以
to go to a silly dance, so...
我们去参加了东村区的一个诗朗诵会
we went to a poetry slam in the east village instead.
回忆往昔  这是我希望
It was one of those seminal moments
没有错过的重要时刻之一
that I kind of wish I didn't skip out on.
敬那些我们错过的时光
To the things we missed.
也敬我们未曾错过的美好
And to those we didn't.
好的  有进展尽快回话
All right, get back to me as soon as you can.
那些不记名债券还是没进展
Hey! So, still no word on the bearer bonds,
但有越来越多的迹象表明
but it's looking more and more
麦迪森的所谓"课外活动"都是违法的
like Madison's extracurriculars were of a criminal nature.
-你有什么发现  -这是鉴证组发现的
- What'd you find? - It's what CSU found --
一枚古董戒指
An antique ring.
就藏在图书馆书架的后面
It was at the back of the shelf at the library.
肯定是从那本书里漏出来了  但我们查到
Must've slipped out of the book. But we were able to I.D.
这戒指是几周前一起失窃案中丢失的
it as having been stolen in a burglary a few weeks ago.
这戒指是谁的
Who did this ring belong to?
属于一个孩子在菲克罗夫特上学的母亲
Uh, to the mom of a kid who attends Faircroft.
而且在过去三个月里有12家
Turns out that a dozen Faircroft families
子女在菲克罗夫特上学的家庭都失窃了
have been burglarized over the past 3 months,
主要丢的都是手表和珠宝
mainly watches and jewelry.
那想必这些失窃案的案发时间
Let me guess -- the dates of the burglaries
和麦迪森夜不归宿的时间完全吻合
match the dates that Madison was out all night.
-说对了  -她肯定把这些赃物卖了
- Bingo. - She must've fenced what she stole,
所以才能付得起那些信用卡账单
which explains why she was able to pay off her credit cards.
也说明了她为什么一大早就去图书馆
It also explains the early-morning visits to the library.
她肯定把赃物都藏在托尔斯泰的书里
She'd stash her haul in Tolstoy after each burglary,
就算有人发现了她
And if anyone caught on to her,
他们也找不到这些赃物
they'd never be able to find the loot.
就算找到了赃物
And if they did find the loot,
也查不到她头上
they wouldn't be able to connect it to her.
我与麦迪森在学校的所有朋友都核实过了
Well, I checked with all of Madison's friends at school.
谁都不知道她在做什么
None of them seem to know what she was up to.
无记名债券有进展了
Hey, hey. Got a hit on those bearer bonds.
原来  这些债券是在弗洛勒尔帕克
Turns out, they were stolen months ago
的一起银行抢劫案中失窃的
in an armed robbery of a bank in Floral Park.
劫匪把保险箱掠夺一空
The crew cleaned out the safety deposit boxes.
慢着  你是说
Hold up, are you saying
一个17岁的预科生抢了一家银行
that a 17-year-old prep-school girl robbed a bank?
不是  但估计她是把抢银行的人给劫了
No, but she might've robbed the guy who robbed the bank.
根据警方的报告
According to the police report,
银行劫案的主要嫌疑人
the prime suspect in the bank robbery
名叫陈向祖的人
was one Xiangzu Chen,
以前是三合会的打手  后来自己单干
a former triad enforcer who went into business for himself.
地检已经有足够的证据起诉他
Now, the D.A. had enough evidence to indict him,
但他的辩护律师利用技术细节把他救出来了
but his defense attorney got him off on a technicality.
失窃债券从未被发现
The bonds were never recovered.
这和麦迪森又有什么联系
And how does any of this connect with Madison?
看看他的辩护律师是谁
Look who his defense attorney is.
查尔斯·博蒙特  麦迪森的父亲
Charles Beaumont, Madison's father?
麦迪森肯定从她父亲那里听说了债券的事
Madison must've heard about the bonds from her dad,
知道了陈把债券藏在哪  值多少钱
where Chen was hiding them, and how much they were worth.
这对新手小偷来说可是个了不得的成绩
That's a huge score for a budding thief.
如果陈发现了他律师的小女儿
And if Chen found out that his lawyer's little girl
偷了他230万
Stole $2.3 million from him --
这绝对是砸开她脑壳的动机
it'd be motive to bash her skull against the ceiling.
贝克特  我们有麻烦了
Yo, Beckett, we got a problem.
-陈不见了  -他藏起来了
- Chen's gone. - He went into hiding?
他卖了他的房子  昨天搬走了
He put his house on the market, and he moved out yesterday.
这可不像是个无辜的人的反应
That doesn't sound like the actions of an innocent man.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
我们试着追踪他
We're trying to track him down,
但他家里人什么都不说
but no one in his family's talking.
莱恩正在询问他的房地产经纪人
Ryan's bringing in his realtor right now
看看她知不知道她的去向
to see if she knows where he went.
不  我不知道他在哪儿
No. No, I have no idea where he is.
我只知道他宁愿损失一大笔钱
All I know is he was willing to take a huge loss
也要尽快结清交易
to close immediately.
他只想把房子脱手
He just wanted the house out of his name
然后在账户里拿到钱
and the cash in his account.
你打算往哪里汇款
Where were you supposed to send the money?
他给了我一个中国银行的汇款号码
He gave me a routing number to a bank in China.
他有没有告诉你
Did he give you any reason
为什么这么急着脱手
why he was looking to unload so quickly?
他说他生意上需要这笔钱
Well, he said he needed the money for business reasons,
但我知道他有所隐瞒
but I could tell he was hiding something.
我的工作就是了解我卖出的每套房子的每个细节
It's my job to know everything about every home I sell,
所以我打听了一下
so I asked around.
显然  陈先生很迷信
Apparently, Mr. Chen is very superstitious,
-而且据他邻居说  发生了一些事  -什么事
- and according to the neighbors, something happened. - What?
我不知道他们葫芦里卖的什么药
Well, I don't know what they're putting in the water out there,
不过隔壁邻居说
but according to the next-door neighbor,
几天前的晚上  有东西把陈先生和他手下
something chased Mr. Chen and his men
赶出了那间房子
out of the house a few nights ago.
"有东西"是什么意思
What do you mean, "something"?
某种东西  就是…
Some thing, as in...
鬼
A ghost?
这个邻居说他向窗外看
This neighbor said that he looked out his window,
看到院子里的家具都在绕着院子飞
and all of the patio furniture was flying around the yard.
把陈先生吓坏了
It scared the hell out of Mr. Chen.
他和他手下就离开了房子  再也没回去过
He and his men left the house, and he never returned.
当然  他不会我提这种细节
Obviously, that detail was left out of the listing.
陈不仅仅离开了房子
So, Chen didn't just leave his house.
他还离开了这个国家
He left the country.
运输安全管理局证实了他在麦迪森被杀时
TSA confirms that he was on a flight to Shanghai
正在去上海的飞机上
when Madison was murdered.
-他不是凶手  -再说一次他为什么出国
- He's not our killer. - Tell me again why he left the country.
什么事
What?
你不会想听这个的
Well, you're not gonna want to hear this,
但我跟进询问了陈的邻居
but I followed up with Chen's neighbors.
有几个人确认了他们在三天前的晚上
Now, several confirmed seeing
在陈家看到了
what can only be described as a telekinetic event
只能称之为隔空移物的事件
at Chen's property three nights ago.
提醒我一下  德国无记名债券
And remind me how stolen German bearer bonds
怎么跟意念移物没关系来着
have nothing to do with telekinesis.
一定会有合理解释的  好吗
You know, there's a logical explanation, okay?
愿闻其详
I'd love to hear it.
好吧
Okay, fine.
麦迪森知道那些债券就在陈的房子里
Uh, Madison knew that those bonds are in Chen's house.
毕竟她父亲是他的律师
Her father is, after all, his lawyer.
所以她想再发一笔横财
Um, so, she's looking for the next big score.
她决定好好探查一下那间房子
She decides to scope out the house,
但是陈的保镖一直都在附近看着
except Chen's guards are around all the time.
所以在知道陈很迷信后
So, knowing that Chen is superstitious,
她自导自演了一场超自然事件
she stages a supernatural event
好把所有人都赶出去
to scare everyone out of the house.
这还真是...挺合理
That's actually really... logical.
谢谢
Thank you.
但其他事怎么解释  比如食堂里发生的
But what about the other events -- the cafeteria?
她在练习  看是不是真能成功
Dry run, to see if she could pull it off.
还有她的死...也是她自导自演的吗
And her own death -- did she stage that, too?
好吧  你说得对
Okay, fine. All right. You're right.
麦迪森不可能单干这些事
Um, Madison couldn't have done this alone.
所以还有别人参与了
So someone else was involved.
麦迪森一定有个同伙
You know what? Madison had to have had a partner.
说得对  一个能隔空移物的同伙
You're right -- a partner with telekinetic abilities.
或是假装能隔空移物的人
Or someone with the ability to fake it.
麦迪森想独吞的时候  那个同伙就盯上她了
And when Madison wouldn't share, the partner went after her.
只要找到麦迪森的同伙  就能找到凶手
So we find Madison's partner, we'll find the killer.
刚从鉴证组来的消息
Hey. Just heard back from CSU.
他们在陈家里找到了几个指纹
They recovered a number of prints in Chen's house.
和麦迪森的匹配
Matched a set to Madison.
和乔丹呢
And to Jordan?
目前还没有  但他们还在处理中
Not yet, but they're still in process.
他们也检查了
They also examined the patio
陈的家具乱飞的露台
where Chen's furniture earned its frequent-flyer miles.
找到了有蓝色痕迹的脚印
Found shoe prints with traces of blue,
上面还有彩色喷漆
iridescent spray paint on them.
让我猜一下  是天蓝色的
Let me guess -- cerulean blue.
能暂停吗  看那儿  左边
Ooh! Can you freeze that? Look there, on the left.
我看看能不能放大
Let me see if I can zoom in.
就是他  是卢卡斯  他当时在食堂
It's him! It's Lucas. He was at the cafeteria.
而且根据那个喷漆  他显然也去过陈家
And apparently at Chen's place, based on that paint.
所以卢卡斯才是那个有超能力的人  不是乔丹
So, Lucas was the one with the power and not Jordan.
是啊  自导自演这一切的能力
Yeah, the power to stage these events.
可他为什么要做麦迪森的同伙
But why would he be Madison's accomplice?
-他说他讨厌她  -或许他是后来才讨厌她的
- He said that he hated her. - Maybe he came to hate her.
所以他才杀了她
That's why he killed her.
而且既然所有人都觉得
And with everyone assuming
乔丹才是有隔空移物能力的人
what Jordan was the one with the telekinetic abilities,
还有比这更好的撇清嫌疑的办法吗
what better way to throw people off his scent?
就是这儿了
This is it.
那枪可没什么用
That gun's not gonna be much help
卢卡斯可以用念力把它从你手中夺走
when Lucas rips it from your hand with his mind.
卡塞尔  最后一次跟你说
Castle, for the last time,
隔空移物根本就不...
telekinesis is not r--
说完啊
You were saying?
够了
Come on.
我们一定能查出发生了什么事
We're gonna finally figure out what's going on here.
不许动
Don't move.
不是你想的那样的
It's not what you think.
别伤害她
Don't hurt her.
她和这事无关
She had nothing to do with this.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
我没想过要让这一切发生
I never meant for any of this to happen.
我没想过要让人受伤
I never meant for anyone to get hurt.
那我们在你家看到的
So, what we saw at your house,
食堂发生的事  是你干的吗
that event at the cafeteria -- that was you?
你肯定觉得我是个怪胎  对吧
Yeah. You must think I'm a freak, huh?
你怎么做到的
Uh how did you do it?
你理解不了  大多数人都不懂
You wouldn't understand. Most people don't.
这就是我学着隐藏自己的原因
That's why I've learned to hide what I am.
意念移物
Telekinetic.
什么
What?
不是  聪明而已
No -- smart.
你懂的  当你很聪明
You know, people don't like it when you're smart,
做些其他人不明白的事  可不招人喜欢
when you do things that people don't understand.
我是说  你们看到的那些  是我操作的而已
I mean, all that stuff you saw, I rigged.
操作  可你确实让椅子桌子移动了
Rigged? But you made the chairs move, the tables!
是的  做特技是我的一个兴趣
Right. Special effects are kind of my hobby.
事实上  这是件很有意思的事
It's pretty amazing, actually,
像用鱼线  磁铁就能做出来的事情
what you can do with, like, some fishing wire and magnets.
人太好骗了
And people are pretty gullible.
当我看见那些女生欺负乔丹
Now, when I saw those girls being so mean to Jordan,
我只是  只是想制止她们
I just -- I just wanted to make them stop.
我想如果能够让她们害怕她
And I figured if I make them afraid of her,
这些女生就会离她远远的  你知道吗
they'll leave her alone, you know?
所以之后  你就伪造了
So, then, you faked the whole
食堂意念移物事件
telekinetic event at the cafeteria.
没错
Yeah.
他会有什么事吗
What's going to happen to him?
这就要看他干了些什么
That all depends on what he did.
他只是想保护我
He was just trying to protect me.
从来没有人为我做过那些事
I've never had anyone do anything like that for me before.
这件事起作用了
And it worked.
大家都相信了  除了麦迪森
I convinced everybody... except Madison.
她  发现了我所做的事情
She, uh, figured out what I'd done,
她威胁我  说要
and then she threatened to -- to --
要向教导处告发我
to turn me in to the administration
如果我不帮她的话
if I didn't help her.
你知道  知道
And you know -- you know --
你知道他们会怎么处理拿着奖学金的学生
You know what they would do to a scholarship kid
恐吓一屋子学生的事
who terrorized a room full of students?
她让你做了什么
What did she ask you to do?
在韦斯切斯特有所房子
There was a house in, uh -- in Westchester,
她想进到那所房里里面
and she said she needed to get inside.
我要做的就是分散主人的注意力
And I was supposed to create a diversion
把他吓跑
to scare the owner out.
你知道她在那所房子里找什么吗
Do you know what she was after in the house?
不知道  我只想完成她让我做的事情
No. No idea. I just wanted to do whatever she said
这样我才能继续自己的生活
so I could get on with my life.
这就是你杀害她的原因  因为她不放手
Which is why you killed her -- because she wouldn't let you.
不是的  我没有  我没有杀人
No, I-I didn't -- I didn't kill anybody!
卢卡斯  麦迪森正在打一通视频电话
Lucas, Madison was on a face time call
当她被害的时候
when she was killed.
目击证人说看到一股无形的力量
Witnesses reported an invisible force
在屋子里拖拽着她
tossing her around the room.
他们说这是意念移物事件
They described it as a telekinetic event.
刚刚你承认了你的杀人动机
Now, you just admitted to motive.
我们所有的嫌疑人当中
And out of all of our suspects,
只有你才有能力做到
you're the only one capable of pulling that off.
是的
Yeah.
没错  你说对了  是我做的
Yeah, you're right. I did pull that off...
但那是和麦迪森一起做的
with Madison.
那是麦迪森强迫我做的第一件事
It was the first thing Madison forced me to do.
看  我把它做得像是一通视频电话
See, I made it look and sound like a face time call,
但是这  只是一个视频
but it's -- it's just a video.
很显然  她的一个朋友
Apparently, one of her friends
被食堂的表演搞得魂不守舍
was pretty disturbed by the cafeteria stunt,
所以她弄了这个来吓吓她
so she did this to really freak her out.
确实是她朋友描述的那样
Exactly how her friends describe it.
这里  就是结尾  没有特效
Now, here's just the end, with no effects.
-怎么样  -看起来不错
- How was that? - That looked good.
我们回放看一下
Let's play it back.
等她看到这个肯定吓死
She is so gonna freak when she sees this.
她会认为是你那个变态心上人会找上她的
She'll think your psycho sweetheart is coming for her next.
-天啊  -好了  废柴  帮我把威压解下来
All right, loser. Help me get this harness off.
你什么时候做的视频
When did you make this?
上周
Uh, last week.
我把最后一部分处理了之后邮件给了麦迪森
I edited that last part out and e-mailed it to Madison.
杀人凶手肯定拿到了这个
Our killer must've gotten their hands on this.
他们用这个视频来掩盖犯罪事实
They used the video to cover their crime
让目击者认为他们看到了杀人现场
by making witnesses believe they were watching the murder live.
还有谁知道这个视频
Who else knew about this video?
据我所知  只有我  麦迪森
Uh, as far as I know, just me, Madison,
还有麦迪森要捉弄的那个闺蜜
and whichever bitch friend Madison pranked with this.
那个闺蜜就是我们要找的凶手
Then that friend is our killer.
打扰一下
Mind if I cut in?
邓南校长  发生什么事了
Principal Dunnan, what's going on?
我该问问你们两个
I should ask you two that.
在你们的储物柜里  我们发现了这些
We found these inside your lockers,
藏在里面的暗格中
hidden under a false bottom inside.
想要解释一下吗
Care to explain?
让我帮你吧
Let me help you.
所有的这些都是赃物
It's all stolen property
都是麦迪森·博蒙特作案得来的
from thefts connected to Madison Beaumont.
你俩就是她贼帮伙的同伙
The two of you were partners in her little bling ring.
至少麦迪森还挺聪明
At least Madison was smart enough
不会把偷来的东西藏在储物柜里
not to hide her stolen stash in her locker.
不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我从来没见过这些东西
I've never seen that stuff before.
我想你是见过的
I think you have.
我们已经把这里的每件东西
We've matched each one of those items
都和从这里的学生家里
to property that was stolen
偷窃的财物匹配过了
from families that have students enrolled here.
而你们的行动
And we matched your movements
符合这些入室盗窃罪发生的时间
to the times when the burglaries were committed.
你们偷窃就够糟的了  居然还对菲克罗夫特下手
It's bad enough you stole, but from the Faircroft community?
什么都别说  我爸是律师
Don't say a word. My dad's a lawyer.
不管出什么事他都能帮咱俩搞掂
He can get us out of anything.
-包括谋杀吗  -谋杀
- Even murder? - Murder?
当麦迪森独自对那些不记名债券下手时
You must've felt betrayed
你们肯定觉得自己遭到了背叛
when Madison went after those bearer bonds alone.
这可是百年一遇的机会啊  她却不带上你们
Score of a lifetime, and she shut you out.
-所以你们才杀了她对吧  -你在说什么呀
- Is that why you killed her? - Hello?
她被杀的时候我们在城市的另外一边
We were halfway across town when that happened.
有证人可以给我们作证的
There are witnesses.
我们通过视频电话看到她被杀的经过
We saw her being killed on that Facetime call.
你是说这通视频电话吗
You mean this call?
等她看到这个肯定吓死
She is so gonna freak when she sees this.
她会认为是你那个变态心上人会找上她的
She'll think your psycho sweetheart is coming for her next.
-天啊  -好了  废柴  帮我把威压解下来
- Oh, my God. - All right, loser. Help me get this harness off.
你看到的视频电话是麦迪森录好的恶作剧录像
What you saw was a pre-recorded joke video that Madison made.
你看到这段录像的时候  她早就已经死了
By the time you watched it, she was already dead.
凶手用这段录像作为自己的不在场证明
Our killer used it as an alibi
让自己看上去像是在案发当时
to make it look like she was halfway across town
已经跨过这座城市到达另一边了
when the murder happened.
她还特意找了个朋友做证人
She also witnessed it alongside a friend.
所以你以为是实时的视频通话
So what you thought was a Facetime call
实际上只是一段
was actually a video...
在凶手的手机上播放的录像
played on the killer's phone.
我说错了吗  克丽丝
Isn't that right, Kris?
不
No.
-求求你告诉我这不是真的  -什么不是真的
- Please tell me you didn't. - Didn't what?
难道你还想继续跟她玩那套变态游戏吗
Didn't want to play her psycho games anymore?
我只想退出
I just wanted out.
但是当我跟她说的时候  她不许我退出
But when I told her, she wouldn't let me quit.
她说她会毁了我
She said that she would destroy me!
她会毁了我们
That she would destroy us!
所以我就想  既然她已经给我准备好了
So I thought, why should we take the blame
完美的不在场证明  为什么还要被她拖下水呢
when she'd already given me the perfect alibi?
而你只需要将犯罪现场布置得跟录像中一样就行
And all you had to do was match the crime scene to the video,
所以你把麦迪森的血涂到了天花板上
which is why you transferred Madison's blood to the ceiling.
她是拉拉队队长
She is captain of the cheer squad.
她深知怎么爬到金字塔的顶端
She knows her way to the top of the pyramid.
卢卡斯的下场将会如何
So, what's gonna happen to Lucas?
他唯一的罪行就是破门入室
Well, I mean, his only crime was
其中的失物本是赃物  借此机会反而物归原主了
a B&E in which stolen goods were stolen and since recovered,
所以他不会被起诉
so he'll keep his freedom.
我们也会保留他的奖学金  只不过这学期
And his scholarship, although he will be on probation
他将留校察看
for the remainder of the term.
还真是宽大仁慈啊
Leniency, huh?
很高兴见到现如今学校的领导层
Well, nice to see that the administration
比我读书那会有人情味的多
has more compassion now than they did in my day.
我想知道一件事  卡塞尔先生
There's one thing I need to know, Mr. Castle.
这件事我已经琢磨了很多年了
It's haunted me for years.
你们是从哪弄来那头奶牛的
Where did you get the cow?
这么说吧  先生
Put it this way, sir --
如果你想要的话  我认识个熟人可以帮你
if you ever need one, I know a guy.
好了  看着点路
All right, where do you think you're going?
他们看起来玩得很开心啊
They look like they're having fun.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道你很叛逆  你不喜欢跟风
Listen, I know you're a rebel and you hate convention
之类之类的  但是
and blah, blah, blah, but...
凯特  你愿不愿意
Kate, would you, uh...
和我一同参加舞会
will you go to the dance with me?
*你流淌在我的血液中  我无法将你忘怀*
*Oh, you're in my veins and I cannot get you out*
*整晚我嘴里尝到的都是你的味道*
*Oh, you're all I taste at night inside of my mouth*
你后悔吗
Do you regret it --
搞了那场恶作剧  错过了你的毕业舞会
that prank, missing your prom,
没能跟奥德拉·道伯森一起跳舞
not being here with Audra Dobson?
一点都不后悔
Not even a little bit.
我所做过的每件事  每个选择
Everything I've ever done, every choice I've ever made,
发生在我身上的每一件
every...terrible and wonderful thing
坏事和好事
that's ever happened to me --
这一切都是为了引领我走到今天
it's all led me to right here,
这一刻在这里  和你在一起
this moment, with you.
*一切都不同了*
*Nothing stays the same*
我一直很喜欢这首歌
I've always loved this song.
我们是不是已经找到了属于我们的歌
Could it be we just found our song?
*人无完人*
*Nobody here's perfect*
卡塞尔
Castle.
*你依赖的一切*
*Oh, all that you rely on*
*一切*
*O-o-on*
*你可以拯救的一切*
*And all that you can save*
这就是磁性啊
Talk about magnetism. Mm.
*将会在清晨离开你*
*Will leave you in the morning*
对了  我想起来了
Oh, that reminds me --
我让警员清查过卢卡斯的家
I had unis sweep Lucas' house,
你知道他们没找到什么吗
and you know what they didn't find?
绳索  磁铁  所有一切可以用来造成
Wires, magnets, anything that would explain
我们那天看到的东西满天飞的情景的东西
that stuff that we saw flying around.
*你深深地烙印在我的血液中  我无法将你忘怀*
*Oh, you're in my veins and I cannot get you out*
-这不会是  -不会
- You don't think -- - No.
别说话了  吻我吧
Now shut up and kiss me.
*不  我无法将你忘怀*
*No, I cannot get you out*
*你流淌在在我的血液中*
*Oh, you're in my veins*
*不  我无法将你忘怀*
*No, I cannot get you out*